Guide to the Yale Library Associates Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Library Associates records
1927-2011
RU 1145
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
11.93
The records consist of correspondence, Trustee meeting minutes and records, new library acquisition files, and event ephemera from the Yale Library Associates.
Yale Library Associates
Conditions Governing Access
Restricted until January 1, 2047.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, Trustee meeting minutes and records, new library acquisition files, and event ephemera from the Yale Library Associates.
General
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-C (YRG 32-C), Records of Yale University Library departments and offices.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, 2016.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale Library Associates was founded in 1930 "to help keep the Library in its proper position as a great world-collection of books indispensable to the University whose heart and center it constitutes." Supporters are kept informed about Library news, and are invited to lectures, exhibitions, openings, receptions, performances, and symposia throughout the year.
Yale Library Associates
- Records, 1927-2011; Accession 2017-A-027
  - Yale Library Associates Administrative Records
    - General files, 1964-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Contributions
      - 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence A-L (Prior to 1977), 1964-1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence M-Z (Prior to 1977), 1966-1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: ex-members, deceased, old correspondence (Prior to 1977), 1966-1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Dickens Exhibition, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Exhibitions (Sponsored by the Associates), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Federal Tax Status, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Form Letters, 1959-1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Form Letters, 1970-1976 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Gift memos
      - 1970 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - King Lear- Pledges, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Membership Lists: Alphabetical, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Membership Lists: Geographical, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Newsletters
      - 1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 1976 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Rabinowitz List, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Request for Services, 1971-1976 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Walpole Concert- Special Account, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Walpole Exhibition, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Walpole Jubillee
      - General, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Guest and Dinner List, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence
      - General
        - A-B, 1977-2000 (Box 2, Folder 35)
        - C-F, 1984-2000 (Box 2, Folder 36)
        - G-H, 1978-1999 (Box 2, Folder 37)
        - J-L, 1977-1997 (Box 2, Folder 38)
        - M-N, 1978-1998 (Box 2, Folder 39)
        - O-R, 1977-2001 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        - S-T, 1981-1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
        - V-Z, 1977-1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - G. Arader Correspondence, 1982-1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Beinecke Correspondence, 1980-1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Gordon Haight Files, 1978-1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Herman Liebert Files, 1972-1995 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - MacKinnon Correspondence YLA Chairman, 2000-2003 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
      - Joe Reed Correspondence (YLA Chairman)
        - 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
        - 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
        - 1990-1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        - 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 14)
        - 1997-2000 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - W. Reese, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Witten, L., 1981-1991 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - YLA Ad- Yale Alumni Magazine, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - YLA Annual Events and Costs, 1981-1988 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Beinecke Building and Collections for Docents, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Constitution for Yale Library Association, 1960-2001 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Beinecke Family, 1997-2001 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Beinecke Theft, 2001 Summer (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Bibliophiles Tour
      - 1986 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - 1988 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - 2003 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Information - Places to visit, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Biographies, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Brochure and P.R.: Bookmark, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - A Celebration of Noel Coward Brochure, 2001 December (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Yale Library Association (YLA) Ephemera, Undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Yale Library Association (YLA) Endowment Fund
      - Letters, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Executive Committee Meetings, 1982-1985 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Ralph Franklin's and Larry Dowler's Letters and Memos, 1983-1993 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Friends Groups: Requests for Information, 1978-1999 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Invitation to Join Letters, 1983-1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Invitations, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Jared Eliot Associates, 1972-1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Marinetti and Futurism Exhibition, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Membership Ads: public relations, 1986-1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - YLA Membership Contributions
      - 1977-1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - 1987-1994 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - 1995-2002 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - YLA Membership Correspondence
      - 2001 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 12A)
    - Membership Numbers, 1981-1989 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - New, Renew, Letters, 1982-1991 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - YLA Newsletters, 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Reference Lists, 1987-2003 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Renewal Letters, 1999-2001 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - December Renewal Letters, 1977-1993 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - 75th Anniversary and 5-year plan, 2001-2004 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - SML Collections and Articles, 1978-1989 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - YLA Membership Correspondence
      - 1961-1978 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - 1979-1990 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - 1991-2003 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Carl Van Vechten Exhibition, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Library Association Volunteers, 1977-1982 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - American Antiquarian Society, 1983-1989 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Amherst Library, 1984-1993 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Bancroft, 1982-1986 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - John Carter Brown, 1982-1986 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Chicago, University of, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Columbia University Library, 1964, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Folger Library, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Friends of Library Groups Elsewhere, 1982-1989 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Harvard University, 1984-1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - New York Public Library, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Pierpont Morgan Library, 1983-1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Princeton University, 1984-1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Yale Art Gallery/British Art Center (BAC), 1983-2000 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Yale-Friends of American Art, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Other Library Sample Brochures, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Yale Publications, 1984-1988 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Bibliophiles Tour, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Preliminaries-Bibliophiles Tour, 2003-2005 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - YLA Gifts, 2004-2005 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Gifts of $500+, 2002-2008 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Letters from YLA, 2004-2006 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Letters to YLA, 2004-2005 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Osborn Index List, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Renewal Letter YLA, 2003-2005 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - YLA Signatures, Undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Thank you correspondence, 1995-2002 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Yale Library Associates Visitors Book, 1948-1960 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - The Register of Yale Library Associates, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Yale Library Associates Literary Gazette Records
    - Drafts and correspondence
      - Blum, Harold, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Dickens, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Drew, Fraser, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Eberstadt, Edward, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Jonas, Klaus, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Lang, Cecil, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - McClintock, Walter, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Rogers, Bruce, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Saint Gauden, Augustus, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Sizer, Theodore, 1959-1965 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, 1952-1961 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence, 1957-1962 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Permissions, 1972-1979 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Galleys-correspondence, 1949-1979 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Articles promised, 1961-1966 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Daniel Defoe- A Crusoe in Scotland, Henry C. Hutchins (Not published), 1950 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - General, 1927-1952 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Acquisitions and Correspondence
      - 1962 October (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - 1963 January (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - 1963 July (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - 1963 October (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - 1964 January (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - 1964 April (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - 1964 July (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - 1964 October (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - 1965 April (Box 8, Folder 26)
      - 1965 July (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - 1965 October (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - 1966 January (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - 1966 April (Box 8, Folder 30)
      - 1966 July (Box 8, Folder 31)
      - 1966 October (Box 8, Folder 32)
      - 1967 January (Box 8, Folder 33)
      - 1967 April (Box 8, Folder 34)
      - 1967 July (Box 8, Folder 35)
      - 1967 October (Box 8, Folder 36)
      - 1968 January (Box 8, Folder 37)
      - 1968 April (Box 8, Folder 38)
      - 1968 July (Box 8, Folder 39)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 40)
      - 1969 October (Box 8, Folder 41)
      - 1970 January (Box 8, Folder 42)
      - 1970 April (Box 8, Folder 43)
      - 1970 July (Box 8, Folder 44)
      - 1970 October (Box 8, Folder 45)
      - 1971 January (Box 8, Folder 46)
      - 1971 April (Box 8, Folder 47)
      - 1971 July (Box 8, Folder 48)
      - 1971 October (Box 8, Folder 49)
        - 1972 January (Box 8, Folder 50)
      - 1972 April (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - 1972 July (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - 1972 October (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - 1973 January (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - 1973 April (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - 1973 July (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - 1973 October (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - 1974 January (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - 1974 April (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - 1974 July (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - 1974 October (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - 1975 January (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - 1975 April (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - 1975 July (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - 1975 October (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - 1976 January (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - 1976 April (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - 1976 July (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - 1976 October (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - 1977 January (Box 9, Folder 20-21)
      - 1977 April (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - 1977 July (Box 9, Folder 23)
      - 1977 October (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - 1978 January (Box 9, Folder 25)
      - 1978 April (Box 9, Folder 26)
      - 1978 July (Box 9, Folder 27)
      - 1978 October (Box 9, Folder 28)
      - 1979 January (Box 9, Folder 29)
      - 1979 April (Box 9, Folder 30)
      - 1979 July (Box 9, Folder 31)
      - 1979 October (Box 9, Folder 32)
      - 1980 January (Box 9, Folder 33)
      - 1980 April (Box 9, Folder 34)
      - 1980 July (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - 1981 January (Box 9, Folder 36)
      - 1981 April-October (Box 9, Folder 37)
      - 1982 January-October (Box 9, Folder 38)
      - 1982 July-1983 October (Box 9, Folder 39)
      - 1984 April (Box 9, Folder 40)
      - 1984 October (Box 9, Folder 41)
      - 1985 April (Box 9, Folder 42)
      - 1985 October (Box 9, Folder 43)
      - 1986 April (Box 9, Folder 44)
      - 1986 October (Box 9, Folder 45)
      - 1987 April (Box 9, Folder 46)
      - 1987 October (Box 9, Folder 47)
      - 1988 April (Box 9, Folder 48)
      - 1988 October (Box 9, Folder 49)
      - 1989 April (Box 9, Folder 50)
      - 1989 October (Box 9, Folder 51)
      - 1990 April (Box 9, Folder 52)
      - 1990 October (Box 9, Folder 53)
      - 1991 April (Box 9, Folder 54)
      - 1991 October (Box 9, Folder 55)
      - 1992 April (Box 9, Folder 56)
      - 1992 October (Box 9, Folder 57)
      - 1993 April (Box 9, Folder 58)
      - 1993 October (Box 9, Folder 59)
      - 1994 April (Box 9, Folder 60)
      - 1994 October (Box 9, Folder 61)
      - 1995 April (Box 9, Folder 62)
      - 1995 October (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - 1996 October (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - 1997 April (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - 1997 October (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - 1998 April (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1986-2000 (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
    - Correspondence- Obsolete, 2000-2004 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence- Current, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Issues autographed by Carl Van Vetchen, 1964-1982 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Acquisitions reports-Beinecke Library, 1963-1967 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - YUL Gazette Article Reprints, 1947-1981 (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
    - Press clippings
      - 1991 April (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - 1991 October (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - 1992 April (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - 1992 October (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - 1993 April (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - 1993 October (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - 1994 April (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - 1994 October (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - 1995 April (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - 1995 October (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - 1996 April (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - 1997 April (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - 1997 October (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - 1998 April (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - 1998 October (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - 1999 April (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - 1999 October (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - 2000 April (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - 2000 October (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - 2001 April (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - 2001 October (Box 12, Folder 21)
      - 2002 April (Box 12, Folder 22)
      - 2002 October (Box 12, Folder 23)
      - 2003 April (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Yale Library Associates Events
    - Invitations
      - 1950-1970 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - 1970-1979 (Box 13, Folder 2-3)
      - 1980-1987 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - 1988-1990 (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
    - Selected acquisitions for exhibits
      - 1984 November-1988 October (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - 1989 April-1992 October (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - 1993 April-1998 October (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - 1999 April-2002 October (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - 2003 May-2005 October (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - 2006 May-2008 October (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - "A Celebration of Noel Coward" video recording, 2001 December 6; 1 (Box 38)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.